<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<label auto="true" type="str" verify="true"><![CDATA[Other]]></label>
	<author auto="true" type="list" verify="true">
		<item type="str"><![CDATA[AndrewYaremko]]></item>
	</author>
	<date auto="true" type="str" verify="true"><![CDATA[2022-10-17, 02:45]]></date>
	<link auto="true" type="str" verify="true"><![CDATA[https://habr.com/ru/post/693670/]]></link>
	<title auto="true" type="str" verify="true"><![CDATA[Бизнес культура и копирайтинг. Эволюция заголовков iPhone]]></title>
	<categories auto="true" type="list" verify="true">
		<item type="str"><![CDATA[Веб-дизайн]]></item>
		<item type="str"><![CDATA[Управление продуктом]]></item>
		<item type="str"><![CDATA[Копирайт]]></item>
	</categories>
	<key_words auto="true" type="list" verify="true">
		<item type="str"><![CDATA[копирайтинг]]></item>
		<item type="str"><![CDATA[маркетинг]]></item>
		<item type="str"><![CDATA[iphone]]></item>
		<item type="str"><![CDATA[культура разработки]]></item>
		<item type="str"><![CDATA[культура компании]]></item>
		<item type="str"><![CDATA[культура организации]]></item>
	</key_words>
	<text auto="true" type="str" verify="true"><![CDATA[Докинз выдвинул теорию об эволюции биологических видов, ключевым звеном в которой выступает «Эгоистичный ген». В рамках нее, была также представлена концепция мемов, для снятия возражений о культурной составляющей социума сапиенсов. Мем, как репликатор культурного кода, также часть эволюционного процесса.
Проецирование Меметики на «Бизнес культуру» снимает противоречия между заказчиками-компаниями и теми, кто обычно и как обычно ее выстраивает. Те четким определением маркеров этой культуры — Бизнес мемов, а не смузи в столовках, лонгбордах в модных офисах на Таганке и образовательных программ.
«Реверс-инжениринг» такого репликатора, я проведу на том, что является по моему мнению лакмусовой бумажкой бизнес культуры — продуктовый копирайтинг. 
В рамках материала я рассматриваю эволюцию часть культурного кода - мема, одного информационного блока — интродукции продукта iPhone за всю его историю. Аспекты связанные с развитием интернета, расширением линейки, эволюции TOV - tone of voice, структуры блока и его содержания, зависимость от него всего сторителлинга станицы, а также заимствования и тупиковые ветки. 
Термины, которыми мне удобно пользоваться для классификации смыслов:
интродукция — набор интерфейсов и элементов отвечающих задаче краткого представления с продуктом;
Белиф/в — обещание качественных изменений в жизни человека;
Бенефит — конкретное изменение в образе жизни или опыте связанное с конкретной функцией продукта;
TOV — термин я использую как общий характер фразы (не совсем корректно, но коротко).
Заголовки
iPhone
Introducing iPhone
iPhone 3G
Twice as fast. Half the price.
Phone, iPod, Internet, and more.
iPhone 3G s
The fastest, most powerful iPhone yet.
Introducing iPhone 3G S
iPhone 4
This changes everything. Again.
iPhone 4. In so many ways, it’s a first.
iPhone 4 s
It’s the most amazing iPhone yet.
Picking up where amazing left off.
iPhone 5
The biggest thing to happen to iPhone since iPhone.
So much more than before. And so much less, too.
iPhone 5 s
Forward thinking.
iPhone 5 c
For the colorful.
iPhone 6
Bigger than bigger
iPhone 6 c
The only thing that’s changed is everything.
iPhone 7
This is 7.
iPhone X
———
iPhone 8
A beautiful mind.
iPhone Xs
Welcome to the big screens.
iPhone XR
Brilliant. In every way.
iPhone 11
Just the right amount of everything.
iPhone 11 Pro
And then there was Pro.
iPhone SE
Lots to love. Less to spend.
iPhone 12 Pro
It’s a leap year.
iPhone 12
Blast past fast.
iPhone 13 Pro
Oh. So. Pro.
iPhone 13
Your new superpower.
iPhone 14
Big and bigger.
iPhone 14 Pro
Pro. Beyond.
Introducing iPhone
iPhone | 2007
iPhone combines three products — a revolutionary mobile phone, a widescreen iPod with touch controls, and a breakthrough Internet communications device with desktop-class email, web browsing, maps, and searching — into one small and lightweight handheld device. iPhone also introduces an entirely new user interface based on a large multi-touch display and pioneering new software, letting you control everything with just your fingers. So it ushers in an era of software power and sophistication never before seen in a mobile device, completely redefining what you can do on a mobile phone.
2007 — длинные лендинг-пейджи еще не изобретены, а новый класс устройств компании еще не оброс версионностью железа и по. За сим, адрес /iphone полностью посвящен презентации продукта, на котором собраны все информационные элементы дожившие до сегодняшнего дня:
название
изображение
слоган
описание — далее трансформируется в адженду
keyfeature блок — далее трансформируется в слайдер, а затем только в адженду
просмотр — ссылки на выступление и рекламного ролика
TOV — знакомство с новым классом устройств. Перечисляются функциональные особенности и возможности, используются аналогии с привычными вещами и сервисами. Последняя фраза — откровенный обещание того, как изменится в целом жизнь пользователя — бенефит о мобилизации части жизни человека «what you can do on a mobile phone». Далее такой подход станет еще ярче в TOV компании во всех продуктах.
Keyfeature блок вторит навигации — количеству продуктовых страниц.
Twice as fast. Half the price. Phone, iPod, Internet, and more
iPhone 3G | 2008
Introducing iPhone 3G. With fast 3G wireless technology, GPS mapping, support for enterprise features like Microsoft Exchange, and the new App Store, iPhone 3G puts even more features at your fingertips. And like the original iPhone, it combines three products in one — a revolutionary phone, a widescreen iPod, and a breakthrough Internet device with rich HTML email and a desktop-class web browser. iPhone 3G. It redefines what a mobile phone can do — again.
Страница /iphone отныне посвящена всей экосистеме устройств и мобильной ос. Что вносит большие изменения в introduction блок, разбивая знакомство на 2 страницы. Такое разделение останется стандартом и по сей день. 
Пропало описание, но keyfeature блок обзавелся коротким описание к каждому пункту и является частью внутренней навигации страницы продукта. 
Описание и второй заголовок отображаются на второй, внутренней странице Features. 
Как и в прошлом варианте — перечисление функций и резюмирование Бенефитом об изменении мобильного опыта человека. Вариации на тему «мы все изменили снова» — станут частью TOV. 
На этой итерации можно говорить о последовательности раскрытия информации и зачатках сторителлинга.
The fastest, most powerful iPhone yet.
iPhone 3G S | 2009 
Meet the fastest, most powerful iPhone yet. iPhone 3GS features video recording, Voice Control, up to 32GB of storage, and more.
Закончилась беготня с экстренным внедрением AppStore, а посему, акцент снова на устройстве. В этой итерации мы получаем актуальный и по сей день вид страницы продукта — лонгрид.
Keyfeature блок становится слайдером. Описание и заголовок — на второй странице — Features. При этом, название продукта с тизерной страницы становится заголовком на второй, а заголовок — частью описания. Которая теперь — полноценная адженда, с прямой последовательностью раскрытия. 
TOV — «спасибо Кэп» очевидное сравнение и преимущества с предыдущей моделью. Перечисление функциональных характеристик продукта. Бенефитов и беливов в данной итерации нет. 

This changes everything. Again.In so many ways, it’s a first.
iPhone 4 | 2010
While everyone else was busy trying to keep up with iPhone, we were busy creating amazing new features that make iPhone more powerful, easier to use, and more indispensable than ever. The result is iPhone 4. The biggest thing to happen to iPhone since iPhone.
Два заголовка, слайдер и описание на странице Features. Первый заголовок и список нововведений находится на странице с анонсом в виде слайдера. 
В описании юмор и сравнение с предыдущими моделями и бенефиты для пользователя — easier to use, and more indispensable. Отдельно, белив о такой же революции (новых ощущениях) как и первый iphone.
It’s the most amazing iPhone yet.
iPhone 4 S | 2011 
Dual-core A5 chip. All-new 8MP Camera and optics. iOS 5 and iCloud. And introducing Siri.
Picking up where amazing left off.
The dual-core A5 chip delivers even more power. The 8MP camera with all-new optics also shoots 1080p HD video. And with Siri, iPhone 4S does what you ask. Talk about amazing.
Данная итерация усложнена избыточными и повторяющимися элементами: две адженды, 2 заголовка, слайдер, keyfeature блок на второй странице, который вторит слайдеру.
Анонсный блок содержит сокращенную адженду, заголовок и слайдер. Страница продукта — заголовок, расширенную адженду той же последовательности и отдельный перечень нововведений вторящий адженде, по которому выстраивается сторителлинг страницы.
Адженда заканчивается бенефитом, что человек получает себе помощника, и обещание — интересные разговоры.
Заголовок перекликается с таковым в iPhone 3G S
The biggest thing to happen to iPhone since iPhone.So much more than before. And so much less, too. 
iPhone 5 | 2012 
A remarkably slim design that still makes room for a larger display and a faster chip. Ultrafast wireless that doesn’t sacrifice battery life. And all-new headphones designed to sound great and fit comfortably. So much went into this iPhone. So you could get even more out of it.
Дизайн упростился, ушла адженда, остался слайдера на странице странице /iphone вместе с заголовком и на странице продукта в разделе Features.
Описание частично повторяет адженду/слайдер, но имеет больший эмоциональный окрас. Заканчивается обещанием получения большего опыта. 
Заголовок на странице продукта — это бенефит из второго слайда. 
По характеру слайдер похож на итерацию с iPhone 4 — не перечисление характеристик функций, а перечень бенефитов — как изменится жизнь пользователя.  
Заголовок вторит финальному обещанию из описания iphone 4.
Forward thinkingFor the colorful
iPhone 5 S / C | 2013
Большой шаг в упрощении — получаем уже привычную конструкцию тизера: наименование и заголовок. Однако, обе модели располагаются не отдельными блоками, а в одном слайдере. 
К сожалению параллакс конструкция страниц не позволяет вытащить больше информации. Каждая модель обзаводится своим адресом, а features перестает быть страницей на которую попадаешь по клику на тизер. 
Оба заголовка начинаются с FOR
Bigger than bigger
iPhone 6 | 2014 
iPhone 6 isn’t simply bigger — it’s better in every way. Larger, yet dramatically thinner. More powerful, but remarkably power efficient. With a smooth metal surface that seamlessly meets the new Retina HD display. It’s one continuous form where hardware and software function in perfect unison, creating a new generation of iPhone that’s better by any measure.
С этого момента начинается классика: собственный адрес продукта, структура тизера и продуктовой страницы актуальная и по сей день: тизер — Название и заголовок, продуктовая страница — Название, заголовок, изображение, адженда и ссылки на фильм и презентацию.
TOV — через прилагательные обозначаются характеристики продукта, но без уточнения, намекая на бенефиты, которые получит пользователь.
The only thing that’s changed is everything.
iPhone 6S | 2015 
The moment you use iPhone 6s, you know you’ve never felt anything like it. With just a single press, 3D Touch lets you do more than ever before. Live Photos bring your memories to life in a powerfully vivid way. And that’s just the beginning. Take a deeper look at iPhone 6s, and you’ll find innovation on every level.
TOV — акцент на пользователе — обещания изменить жизнь пользователя и получения бенефитов при использовании. 
Графический блок сильно вытянут и адженда располагается сразу за ним. Развитие этой идеи мы увидим много позже, в iphone 14. Чему будет способствовать заигрывание с считыванием аджанты в iPhone 13.
A big step for small.
iPhone SE | 2016 
Welcome to iPhone SE, the most powerful 4‑inch phone ever. To create it, we started with a beloved design, then reinvented it from the inside out. The A9 is the same advanced chip used in iPhone 6s. The 12 megapixel camera captures incredible photos and 4K videos. And Live Photos bring your images to life. The result is an iPhone that looks small. But lives large.
TOV— через прилагательные обозначаются характеристики продукта, но без уточнения, намекая на бенефиты, которые получит пользователь.
Отсутствие бенефитов и беликов в описании связано с запуском двух моделей в этом году. В описании второго продукта — все обещания на месте. Такой подход станет стандартом в последующем.
This is 7.
iPhone 7 | 2016 
iPhone 7 dramatically improves the most important aspects of the iPhone experience. It introduces advanced new camera systems. The best performance and battery life ever in an iPhone. Immersive stereo speakers. The brightest, most colorful iPhone display. Splash and water resistance.1 And it looks every bit as powerful as it is. This is iPhone 7.
Наименование продукта и заголовок объединены — это отсылка к первым двум заголовкам, аля Introducing iPhone.
TOV — обещание в новых ощущениях от использования уже знакомого опыта, что передано гиперболизировпнное перечислением улучшений ключевых функций.
Заголовка нет
iPhone X | 2017 
Our vision has always been to create an iPhone that is entirely screen. One so immersive the device itself disappears into the experience. And so intelligent it can respond to a tap, your voice, and even a glance. With iPhone X, that vision is now a reality. Say hello to the future.
TOV — подмена понятий — выдача запроса клиентов как своих желаний. Обещание исполнения как бы ожидаемых новых впечатлений и опыта.
A beautiful mind.
iPhone 8 | 2017 
iPhone 8 introduces an all‑new glass design. The world’s most popular camera, now even better. The smartest, most powerful chip ever in a smartphone. Wireless charging that’s truly effortless. And augmented reality experiences never before possible. iPhone 8. A new generation of iPhone.
TOV — гиперболизировпнное перечисление характеристик с неявно выраженным обещанием получить ожидаемое но в новом поколении.
Welcome to the big screens.
iPhone XS | 2018 
Super Retina in two sizes — including the largest display ever on an iPhone. Even faster Face ID. The smartest, most powerful chip in a smartphone. And a breakthrough dual-camera system with Depth Control. iPhone XS is everything you love about iPhone. Taken to the extreme.
TOV — перечисление характеристик заканчивается беловом о любимом устройстве и его совершенной форме.
Brilliant. In every way.
iPhone XR | 2018 
All-new Liquid Retina display — the most advanced LCD in the industry. Even faster Face ID. The smartest, most powerful chip in a smartphone. And a breakthrough camera system with Depth Control. iPhone XR. It’s beautiful any way you look at it.
TOV — обещание иметь «красивую» штучку — вещь, которая будет нравится, в том числе по техническим характеристикам.
Just the right amount of everything.
iPhone 11 | 2019 
A new dual‑camera system captures more of what you see and love. The fastest chip ever in a smartphone and all‑day battery life let you do more and charge less. And the highest‑quality video in a smartphone, so your memories look better than ever.
TOV — три бенефита выраженные через особенности характеристик устройства.
And then there was Pro.
iPhone 11 Pro | 2019 
A transformative triple‑camera system that adds tons of capability without complexity. An unprecedented leap in battery life. And a mind‑blowing chip that doubles down on machine learning and pushes the boundaries of what a smartphone can do. Welcome to the first iPhone powerful enough to be called Pro.
TOV — обозначена уникальность продукта по отношению к своей же линейки. Поэтому бенефиты обозначены через возможности устройства.
Lots to love. Less to spend.
iPhone 11 SE | 2019 
iPhone SE packs our most powerful chip into our most popular size at our most affordable price. It’s just what you’ve been waiting for.
TOV — обещание исполнения желаний подкрепленное очевидностью в характеристиках устройства.
It’s a leap year.
iPhone 12 Pro | 2020 
5G goes Pro. A14 Bionic rockets past every other smartphone chip. The Pro camera system takes low-light photography to the next level — with an even bigger jump on iPhone 12 Pro Max. And Ceramic Shield delivers four times better drop performance. Let’s see what this thing can do.
TOV — три бенефита выраженные через особенности характеристик устройства.
Blast past fast.
iPhone 12  | 2020 — link
5G speed. A14 Bionic, the fastest chip in a smartphone. An edge-to-edge OLED display. Ceramic Shield with four times better drop performance. And Night mode on every camera. iPhone 12 has it all — in two perfect sizes.
TOV — без бенефитов и беливов, простое перечисление характеристик устройства. 
Oh. So. Pro.
iPhone 13 Pro | 2021 
A dramatically more powerful camera system. A display so responsive, every interaction feels new again. The world’s fastest smartphone chip. Exceptional durability. And a huge leap in battery life.
TOV — гиперболизированные преимущества характеристик устройства. Из явно выраженных — только белив о новых ощущениях.
Адженда оформлена в формате — «нечитал», крупно и акцентно выделяет каждое предложение при скролинге. Развитие этого решения получит следущее поколение устройств.
Your new superpower.
iPhone 13 | 2021
A lightning fast chip. A leap in battery life. And all new photo and video capabilities. iPhone 13 lets you do things you never could before — in two great sizes.
TOV — белиф о суперсиле в заголовке и он же повторяется в аджэнтэ. Белив, который подчеркивает одну из новых характеристик — два размера.
Начиная с предидущего поколения, за месяц до выпуска нового. продуктовые страницы устройств меняют свою структуру. Об этом я подробно писал в 2021 году. С данным поколением случилось тоже самое. И эта модифицированная версия также внесла свою лепку в отображение адженды для нового поколения.
Big and bigger.
iPhone 14 | 2022
Our longest battery life ever. Emergency SOS via satellite. A huge leap in low-light photos. Wonderfull.
Заголовок вторит такому же iPhone 6. А адженда оборачивает обещание в одно слово — Wonderfull.
Вместе с тем, через проверенную итерацию с модификацией продуктовых страниц прошлого поколения (еще доступна на русском домене по адресу https://www.apple.com/ru/iphone-13-pro/key-features/), страница снова прирастает блоком keyfeatures по аналогии с iPhone 4 S.
P.S.
Теперь, глядя на продуктовую страницу iPhone становится понятно, откуда, как и зачем появился каждый элемент и какой путь развития он прошел, как самостоятельный в TOV, так и то что менялось под влиянием внешней среды — технологического развития и расширения продуктовой линейки.
Такой цифровой продукт как «интродукция», очень похож на организм с набором кода от своих предшественников, с доминантным и рецессивным набором характеристик. А это значит, что у него были родители, которые холили, воспитывали и учили, как минимум арт-директор и продуктовый редактор, которые распространяли накопленный опыт конечным исполнителям. Тратя на это свое время и время исполнителей. HR назовет это образованием, но корректно относится к этому как к репликации, ибо образование новых копирайтеров и дизайнеров идет строго в рамках «выживания эгоистичного мема». Но более корректная аналогия с институцией. Тк каждая передача кода происходила под четким надзором систем аналитики и выстроенных процессов по ретраспективам. Что и вырисовывается в конечном счете в бизнес культуру. Докинз выдвинул теорию об эволюции биологических видов, ключевым звеном в которой выступает «Эгоистичный ген». В рамках нее, была также представлена концепция мемов, для снятия возражений о культурной составляющей социума сапиенсов. Мем, как репликатор культурного кода, также часть эволюционного процесса. Проецирование Меметики на «Бизнес культуру» снимает противоречия между заказчиками-компаниями и теми, кто обычно и как обычно ее выстраивает. Те четким определением маркеров этой культуры — Бизнес мемов, а не смузи в столовках, лонгбордах в модных офисах на Таганке и образовательных программ.   «Реверс-инжениринг» такого репликатора, я проведу на том, что является по моему мнению лакмусовой бумажкой бизнес культуры — продуктовый копирайтинг.  В рамках материала я рассматриваю эволюцию часть культурного кода - мема, одного информационного блока — интродукции продукта iPhone за всю его историю. Аспекты связанные с развитием интернета, расширением линейки, эволюции TOV - tone of voice, структуры блока и его содержания, зависимость от него всего сторителлинга станицы, а также заимствования и тупиковые ветки.  Термины, которыми мне удобно пользоваться для классификации смыслов: интродукция — набор интерфейсов и элементов отвечающих задаче краткого представления с продуктом;
Белиф/в — обещание качественных изменений в жизни человека;
Бенефит — конкретное изменение в образе жизни или опыте связанное с конкретной функцией продукта;
TOV — термин я использую как общий характер фразы (не совсем корректно, но коротко). интродукция — набор интерфейсов и элементов отвечающих задаче краткого представления с продуктом; интродукция — набор интерфейсов и элементов отвечающих задаче краткого представления с продуктом; Белиф/в — обещание качественных изменений в жизни человека; Белиф/в — обещание качественных изменений в жизни человека; Бенефит — конкретное изменение в образе жизни или опыте связанное с конкретной функцией продукта; Бенефит — конкретное изменение в образе жизни или опыте связанное с конкретной функцией продукта; TOV — термин я использую как общий характер фразы (не совсем корректно, но коротко). TOV — термин я использую как общий характер фразы (не совсем корректно, но коротко). Заголовки iPhone
Introducing iPhone
iPhone 3G
Twice as fast. Half the price.
Phone, iPod, Internet, and more.
iPhone 3G s
The fastest, most powerful iPhone yet.
Introducing iPhone 3G S
iPhone 4
This changes everything. Again.
iPhone 4. In so many ways, it’s a first.
iPhone 4 s
It’s the most amazing iPhone yet.
Picking up where amazing left off.
iPhone 5
The biggest thing to happen to iPhone since iPhone.
So much more than before. And so much less, too.
iPhone 5 s
Forward thinking.
iPhone 5 c
For the colorful.
iPhone 6
Bigger than bigger
iPhone 6 c
The only thing that’s changed is everything.
iPhone 7
This is 7.
iPhone X
———
iPhone 8
A beautiful mind.
iPhone Xs
Welcome to the big screens.
iPhone XR
Brilliant. In every way.
iPhone 11
Just the right amount of everything.
iPhone 11 Pro
And then there was Pro.
iPhone SE
Lots to love. Less to spend.
iPhone 12 Pro
It’s a leap year.
iPhone 12
Blast past fast.
iPhone 13 Pro
Oh. So. Pro.
iPhone 13
Your new superpower.
iPhone 14
Big and bigger.
iPhone 14 Pro
Pro. Beyond. iPhone
Introducing iPhone
iPhone 3G
Twice as fast. Half the price.
Phone, iPod, Internet, and more.
iPhone 3G s
The fastest, most powerful iPhone yet.
Introducing iPhone 3G S
iPhone 4
This changes everything. Again.
iPhone 4. In so many ways, it’s a first.
iPhone 4 s
It’s the most amazing iPhone yet.
Picking up where amazing left off.
iPhone 5
The biggest thing to happen to iPhone since iPhone.
So much more than before. And so much less, too.
iPhone 5 s
Forward thinking.
iPhone 5 c
For the colorful.
iPhone 6
Bigger than bigger
iPhone 6 c
The only thing that’s changed is everything.
iPhone 7
This is 7.
iPhone X
———
iPhone 8
A beautiful mind.
iPhone Xs
Welcome to the big screens.
iPhone XR
Brilliant. In every way.
iPhone 11
Just the right amount of everything.
iPhone 11 Pro
And then there was Pro.
iPhone SE
Lots to love. Less to spend.
iPhone 12 Pro
It’s a leap year.
iPhone 12
Blast past fast.
iPhone 13 Pro
Oh. So. Pro.
iPhone 13
Your new superpower.
iPhone 14
Big and bigger.
iPhone 14 Pro
Pro. Beyond. iPhone
Introducing iPhone
iPhone 3G
Twice as fast. Half the price.
Phone, iPod, Internet, and more.
iPhone 3G s
The fastest, most powerful iPhone yet.
Introducing iPhone 3G S
iPhone 4
This changes everything. Again.
iPhone 4. In so many ways, it’s a first.
iPhone 4 s
It’s the most amazing iPhone yet.
Picking up where amazing left off.
iPhone 5
The biggest thing to happen to iPhone since iPhone.
So much more than before. And so much less, too.
iPhone 5 s
Forward thinking.
iPhone 5 c
For the colorful.
iPhone 6
Bigger than bigger
iPhone 6 c
The only thing that’s changed is everything.
iPhone 7
This is 7.
iPhone X
———
iPhone 8
A beautiful mind.
iPhone Xs
Welcome to the big screens.
iPhone XR
Brilliant. In every way.
iPhone 11
Just the right amount of everything.
iPhone 11 Pro
And then there was Pro.
iPhone SE
Lots to love. Less to spend.
iPhone 12 Pro
It’s a leap year.
iPhone 12
Blast past fast.
iPhone 13 Pro
Oh. So. Pro.
iPhone 13
Your new superpower.
iPhone 14
Big and bigger.
iPhone 14 Pro
Pro. Beyond. iPhone
Introducing iPhone
iPhone 3G
Twice as fast. Half the price.
Phone, iPod, Internet, and more.
iPhone 3G s
The fastest, most powerful iPhone yet.
Introducing iPhone 3G S
iPhone 4
This changes everything. Again.
iPhone 4. In so many ways, it’s a first.
iPhone 4 s
It’s the most amazing iPhone yet.
Picking up where amazing left off.
iPhone 5
The biggest thing to happen to iPhone since iPhone.
So much more than before. And so much less, too.
iPhone 5 s
Forward thinking.
iPhone 5 c
For the colorful.
iPhone 6
Bigger than bigger
iPhone 6 c
The only thing that’s changed is everything.
iPhone 7
This is 7.
iPhone X
———
iPhone 8
A beautiful mind.
iPhone Xs
Welcome to the big screens.
iPhone XR
Brilliant. In every way.
iPhone 11
Just the right amount of everything.
iPhone 11 Pro
And then there was Pro.
iPhone SE
Lots to love. Less to spend.
iPhone 12 Pro
It’s a leap year.
iPhone 12
Blast past fast.
iPhone 13 Pro
Oh. So. Pro.
iPhone 13
Your new superpower.
iPhone 14
Big and bigger.
iPhone 14 Pro
Pro. Beyond. iPhone
Introducing iPhone iPhone iPhone Introducing iPhone Introducing iPhone iPhone 3G
Twice as fast. Half the price.
Phone, iPod, Internet, and more. iPhone 3G iPhone 3G Twice as fast. Half the price.
Phone, iPod, Internet, and more. Twice as fast. Half the price.
Phone, iPod, Internet, and more.  iPhone 3G s
The fastest, most powerful iPhone yet.
Introducing iPhone 3G S iPhone 3G s iPhone 3G s The fastest, most powerful iPhone yet.
Introducing iPhone 3G S The fastest, most powerful iPhone yet.
Introducing iPhone 3G S  iPhone 4
This changes everything. Again.
iPhone 4. In so many ways, it’s a first. iPhone 4 iPhone 4 This changes everything. Again.
iPhone 4. In so many ways, it’s a first. This changes everything. Again.
iPhone 4. In so many ways, it’s a first.  iPhone 4 s
It’s the most amazing iPhone yet.
Picking up where amazing left off. iPhone 4 s iPhone 4 s It’s the most amazing iPhone yet.
Picking up where amazing left off. It’s the most amazing iPhone yet.
Picking up where amazing left off.  iPhone 5
The biggest thing to happen to iPhone since iPhone.
So much more than before. And so much less, too. iPhone 5 iPhone 5 The biggest thing to happen to iPhone since iPhone.
So much more than before. And so much less, too. The biggest thing to happen to iPhone since iPhone.
So much more than before. And so much less, too.  iPhone 5 s
Forward thinking. iPhone 5 s iPhone 5 s Forward thinking. Forward thinking. iPhone 5 c
For the colorful. iPhone 5 c iPhone 5 c For the colorful. For the colorful. iPhone 6
Bigger than bigger iPhone 6 iPhone 6 Bigger than bigger Bigger than bigger iPhone 6 c
The only thing that’s changed is everything. iPhone 6 c iPhone 6 c The only thing that’s changed is everything. The only thing that’s changed is everything. iPhone 7
This is 7. iPhone 7 iPhone 7 This is 7. This is 7. iPhone X
——— iPhone X iPhone X ——— ——— iPhone 8
A beautiful mind. iPhone 8 iPhone 8 A beautiful mind. A beautiful mind. iPhone Xs
Welcome to the big screens. iPhone Xs iPhone Xs Welcome to the big screens. Welcome to the big screens. iPhone XR
Brilliant. In every way. iPhone XR iPhone XR Brilliant. In every way. Brilliant. In every way. iPhone 11
Just the right amount of everything. iPhone 11 iPhone 11 Just the right amount of everything. Just the right amount of everything. iPhone 11 Pro
And then there was Pro. iPhone 11 Pro iPhone 11 Pro And then there was Pro. And then there was Pro. iPhone SE
Lots to love. Less to spend. iPhone SE iPhone SE Lots to love. Less to spend. Lots to love. Less to spend. iPhone 12 Pro
It’s a leap year. iPhone 12 Pro iPhone 12 Pro It’s a leap year. It’s a leap year. iPhone 12
Blast past fast. iPhone 12 iPhone 12 Blast past fast. Blast past fast. iPhone 13 Pro
Oh. So. Pro. iPhone 13 Pro iPhone 13 Pro Oh. So. Pro. Oh. So. Pro. iPhone 13
Your new superpower. iPhone 13 iPhone 13 Your new superpower. Your new superpower. iPhone 14
Big and bigger. iPhone 14 iPhone 14 Big and bigger. Big and bigger. iPhone 14 Pro
Pro. Beyond. iPhone 14 Pro iPhone 14 Pro Pro. Beyond. Pro. Beyond. Introducing iPhone iPhone | 2007 2007 2007 iPhone combines three products — a revolutionary mobile phone, a widescreen iPod with touch controls, and a breakthrough Internet communications device with desktop-class email, web browsing, maps, and searching — into one small and lightweight handheld device. iPhone also introduces an entirely new user interface based on a large multi-touch display and pioneering new software, letting you control everything with just your fingers. So it ushers in an era of software power and sophistication never before seen in a mobile device, completely redefining what you can do on a mobile phone. iPhone combines three products — a revolutionary mobile phone, a widescreen iPod with touch controls, and a breakthrough Internet communications device with desktop-class email, web browsing, maps, and searching — into one small and lightweight handheld device. iPhone also introduces an entirely new user interface based on a large multi-touch display and pioneering new software, letting you control everything with just your fingers. So it ushers in an era of software power and sophistication never before seen in a mobile device, completely redefining what you can do on a mobile phone.   2007 — длинные лендинг-пейджи еще не изобретены, а новый класс устройств компании еще не оброс версионностью железа и по. За сим, адрес /iphone полностью посвящен презентации продукта, на котором собраны все информационные элементы дожившие до сегодняшнего дня: название
изображение
слоган
описание — далее трансформируется в адженду
keyfeature блок — далее трансформируется в слайдер, а затем только в адженду
просмотр — ссылки на выступление и рекламного ролика название название изображение изображение слоган слоган описание — далее трансформируется в адженду описание — далее трансформируется в адженду keyfeature блок — далее трансформируется в слайдер, а затем только в адженду keyfeature блок — далее трансформируется в слайдер, а затем только в адженду просмотр — ссылки на выступление и рекламного ролика просмотр — ссылки на выступление и рекламного ролика TOV — знакомство с новым классом устройств. Перечисляются функциональные особенности и возможности, используются аналогии с привычными вещами и сервисами. Последняя фраза — откровенный обещание того, как изменится в целом жизнь пользователя — бенефит о мобилизации части жизни человека «what you can do on a mobile phone». Далее такой подход станет еще ярче в TOV компании во всех продуктах. Keyfeature блок вторит навигации — количеству продуктовых страниц.  Twice as fast. Half the price. Phone, iPod, Internet, and more iPhone 3G | 2008 2008 2008 Introducing iPhone 3G. With fast 3G wireless technology, GPS mapping, support for enterprise features like Microsoft Exchange, and the new App Store, iPhone 3G puts even more features at your fingertips. And like the original iPhone, it combines three products in one — a revolutionary phone, a widescreen iPod, and a breakthrough Internet device with rich HTML email and a desktop-class web browser. iPhone 3G. It redefines what a mobile phone can do — again. Introducing iPhone 3G. With fast 3G wireless technology, GPS mapping, support for enterprise features like Microsoft Exchange, and the new App Store, iPhone 3G puts even more features at your fingertips. And like the original iPhone, it combines three products in one — a revolutionary phone, a widescreen iPod, and a breakthrough Internet device with rich HTML email and a desktop-class web browser. iPhone 3G. It redefines what a mobile phone can do — again.   Страница /iphone отныне посвящена всей экосистеме устройств и мобильной ос. Что вносит большие изменения в introduction блок, разбивая знакомство на 2 страницы. Такое разделение останется стандартом и по сей день.  Пропало описание, но keyfeature блок обзавелся коротким описание к каждому пункту и является частью внутренней навигации страницы продукта.  Описание и второй заголовок отображаются на второй, внутренней странице Features.  Как и в прошлом варианте — перечисление функций и резюмирование Бенефитом об изменении мобильного опыта человека. Вариации на тему «мы все изменили снова» — станут частью TOV.  На этой итерации можно говорить о последовательности раскрытия информации и зачатках сторителлинга.  The fastest, most powerful iPhone yet. iPhone 3G S | 2009  2009 2009 Meet the fastest, most powerful iPhone yet. iPhone 3GS features video recording, Voice Control, up to 32GB of storage, and more. Meet the fastest, most powerful iPhone yet. iPhone 3GS features video recording, Voice Control, up to 32GB of storage, and more.   Закончилась беготня с экстренным внедрением AppStore, а посему, акцент снова на устройстве. В этой итерации мы получаем актуальный и по сей день вид страницы продукта — лонгрид. Keyfeature блок становится слайдером. Описание и заголовок — на второй странице — Features. При этом, название продукта с тизерной страницы становится заголовком на второй, а заголовок — частью описания. Которая теперь — полноценная адженда, с прямой последовательностью раскрытия.  TOV — «спасибо Кэп» очевидное сравнение и преимущества с предыдущей моделью. Перечисление функциональных характеристик продукта. Бенефитов и беливов в данной итерации нет.    This changes everything. Again.In so many ways, it’s a first. iPhone 4 | 2010 2010 2010 While everyone else was busy trying to keep up with iPhone, we were busy creating amazing new features that make iPhone more powerful, easier to use, and more indispensable than ever. The result is iPhone 4. The biggest thing to happen to iPhone since iPhone. While everyone else was busy trying to keep up with iPhone, we were busy creating amazing new features that make iPhone more powerful, easier to use, and more indispensable than ever. The result is iPhone 4. The biggest thing to happen to iPhone since iPhone.   Два заголовка, слайдер и описание на странице Features. Первый заголовок и список нововведений находится на странице с анонсом в виде слайдера.  В описании юмор и сравнение с предыдущими моделями и бенефиты для пользователя — easier to use, and more indispensable. Отдельно, белив о такой же революции (новых ощущениях) как и первый iphone.  It’s the most amazing iPhone yet. iPhone 4 S | 2011  2011 2011 Dual-core A5 chip. All-new 8MP Camera and optics. iOS 5 and iCloud. And introducing Siri. Dual-core A5 chip. All-new 8MP Camera and optics. iOS 5 and iCloud. And introducing Siri. Picking up where amazing left off. Picking up where amazing left off. The dual-core A5 chip delivers even more power. The 8MP camera with all-new optics also shoots 1080p HD video. And with Siri, iPhone 4S does what you ask. Talk about amazing. The dual-core A5 chip delivers even more power. The 8MP camera with all-new optics also shoots 1080p HD video. And with Siri, iPhone 4S does what you ask. Talk about amazing.   Данная итерация усложнена избыточными и повторяющимися элементами: две адженды, 2 заголовка, слайдер, keyfeature блок на второй странице, который вторит слайдеру. Анонсный блок содержит сокращенную адженду, заголовок и слайдер. Страница продукта — заголовок, расширенную адженду той же последовательности и отдельный перечень нововведений вторящий адженде, по которому выстраивается сторителлинг страницы. Адженда заканчивается бенефитом, что человек получает себе помощника, и обещание — интересные разговоры. Заголовок перекликается с таковым в iPhone 3G S  The biggest thing to happen to iPhone since iPhone.So much more than before. And so much less, too.  iPhone 5 | 2012  2012 2012 A remarkably slim design that still makes room for a larger display and a faster chip. Ultrafast wireless that doesn’t sacrifice battery life. And all-new headphones designed to sound great and fit comfortably. So much went into this iPhone. So you could get even more out of it. A remarkably slim design that still makes room for a larger display and a faster chip. Ultrafast wireless that doesn’t sacrifice battery life. And all-new headphones designed to sound great and fit comfortably. So much went into this iPhone. So you could get even more out of it.   Дизайн упростился, ушла адженда, остался слайдера на странице странице /iphone вместе с заголовком и на странице продукта в разделе Features. Описание частично повторяет адженду/слайдер, но имеет больший эмоциональный окрас. Заканчивается обещанием получения большего опыта.  Заголовок на странице продукта — это бенефит из второго слайда.  По характеру слайдер похож на итерацию с iPhone 4 — не перечисление характеристик функций, а перечень бенефитов — как изменится жизнь пользователя.   Заголовок вторит финальному обещанию из описания iphone 4.  Forward thinkingFor the colorful iPhone 5 S / C | 2013 2013 2013   Большой шаг в упрощении — получаем уже привычную конструкцию тизера: наименование и заголовок. Однако, обе модели располагаются не отдельными блоками, а в одном слайдере.  К сожалению параллакс конструкция страниц не позволяет вытащить больше информации. Каждая модель обзаводится своим адресом, а features перестает быть страницей на которую попадаешь по клику на тизер.  Оба заголовка начинаются с FOR  Bigger than bigger iPhone 6 | 2014  iPhone 6 | 2014 2014 iPhone 6 isn’t simply bigger — it’s better in every way. Larger, yet dramatically thinner. More powerful, but remarkably power efficient. With a smooth metal surface that seamlessly meets the new Retina HD display. It’s one continuous form where hardware and software function in perfect unison, creating a new generation of iPhone that’s better by any measure. iPhone 6 isn’t simply bigger — it’s better in every way. Larger, yet dramatically thinner. More powerful, but remarkably power efficient. With a smooth metal surface that seamlessly meets the new Retina HD display. It’s one continuous form where hardware and software function in perfect unison, creating a new generation of iPhone that’s better by any measure.   С этого момента начинается классика: собственный адрес продукта, структура тизера и продуктовой страницы актуальная и по сей день: тизер — Название и заголовок, продуктовая страница — Название, заголовок, изображение, адженда и ссылки на фильм и презентацию. TOV — через прилагательные обозначаются характеристики продукта, но без уточнения, намекая на бенефиты, которые получит пользователь.  The only thing that’s changed is everything. iPhone 6S | 2015  2015 2015 The moment you use iPhone 6s, you know you’ve never felt anything like it. With just a single press, 3D Touch lets you do more than ever before. Live Photos bring your memories to life in a powerfully vivid way. And that’s just the beginning. Take a deeper look at iPhone 6s, and you’ll find innovation on every level. The moment you use iPhone 6s, you know you’ve never felt anything like it. With just a single press, 3D Touch lets you do more than ever before. Live Photos bring your memories to life in a powerfully vivid way. And that’s just the beginning. Take a deeper look at iPhone 6s, and you’ll find innovation on every level.   TOV — акцент на пользователе — обещания изменить жизнь пользователя и получения бенефитов при использовании.  Графический блок сильно вытянут и адженда располагается сразу за ним. Развитие этой идеи мы увидим много позже, в iphone 14. Чему будет способствовать заигрывание с считыванием аджанты в iPhone 13.  A big step for small. iPhone SE | 2016  iPhone SE | 2016 2016 Welcome to iPhone SE, the most powerful 4‑inch phone ever. To create it, we started with a beloved design, then reinvented it from the inside out. The A9 is the same advanced chip used in iPhone 6s. The 12 megapixel camera captures incredible photos and 4K videos. And Live Photos bring your images to life. The result is an iPhone that looks small. But lives large. Welcome to iPhone SE, the most powerful 4‑inch phone ever. To create it, we started with a beloved design, then reinvented it from the inside out. The A9 is the same advanced chip used in iPhone 6s. The 12 megapixel camera captures incredible photos and 4K videos. And Live Photos bring your images to life. The result is an iPhone that looks small. But lives large.   TOV— через прилагательные обозначаются характеристики продукта, но без уточнения, намекая на бенефиты, которые получит пользователь. Отсутствие бенефитов и беликов в описании связано с запуском двух моделей в этом году. В описании второго продукта — все обещания на месте. Такой подход станет стандартом в последующем.  This is 7. iPhone 7 | 2016  2016 2016 iPhone 7 dramatically improves the most important aspects of the iPhone experience. It introduces advanced new camera systems. The best performance and battery life ever in an iPhone. Immersive stereo speakers. The brightest, most colorful iPhone display. Splash and water resistance.1 And it looks every bit as powerful as it is. This is iPhone 7. iPhone 7 dramatically improves the most important aspects of the iPhone experience. It introduces advanced new camera systems. The best performance and battery life ever in an iPhone. Immersive stereo speakers. The brightest, most colorful iPhone display. Splash and water resistance.1 And it looks every bit as powerful as it is. This is iPhone 7.   Наименование продукта и заголовок объединены — это отсылка к первым двум заголовкам, аля Introducing iPhone. TOV — обещание в новых ощущениях от использования уже знакомого опыта, что передано гиперболизировпнное перечислением улучшений ключевых функций. Заголовка нет iPhone X | 2017  iPhone X | 2017 2017 Our vision has always been to create an iPhone that is entirely screen. One so immersive the device itself disappears into the experience. And so intelligent it can respond to a tap, your voice, and even a glance. With iPhone X, that vision is now a reality. Say hello to the future. Our vision has always been to create an iPhone that is entirely screen. One so immersive the device itself disappears into the experience. And so intelligent it can respond to a tap, your voice, and even a glance. With iPhone X, that vision is now a reality. Say hello to the future.   TOV — подмена понятий — выдача запроса клиентов как своих желаний. Обещание исполнения как бы ожидаемых новых впечатлений и опыта.  A beautiful mind. iPhone 8 | 2017  2017 2017 iPhone 8 introduces an all‑new glass design. The world’s most popular camera, now even better. The smartest, most powerful chip ever in a smartphone. Wireless charging that’s truly effortless. And augmented reality experiences never before possible. iPhone 8. A new generation of iPhone. iPhone 8 introduces an all‑new glass design. The world’s most popular camera, now even better. The smartest, most powerful chip ever in a smartphone. Wireless charging that’s truly effortless. And augmented reality experiences never before possible. iPhone 8. A new generation of iPhone.   TOV — гиперболизировпнное перечисление характеристик с неявно выраженным обещанием получить ожидаемое но в новом поколении.  Welcome to the big screens. iPhone XS | 2018  2018 2018 Super Retina in two sizes — including the largest display ever on an iPhone. Even faster Face ID. The smartest, most powerful chip in a smartphone. And a breakthrough dual-camera system with Depth Control. iPhone XS is everything you love about iPhone. Taken to the extreme. Super Retina in two sizes — including the largest display ever on an iPhone. Even faster Face ID. The smartest, most powerful chip in a smartphone. And a breakthrough dual-camera system with Depth Control. iPhone XS is everything you love about iPhone. Taken to the extreme.   TOV — перечисление характеристик заканчивается беловом о любимом устройстве и его совершенной форме.  Brilliant. In every way. iPhone XR | 2018  2018 2018 All-new Liquid Retina display — the most advanced LCD in the industry. Even faster Face ID. The smartest, most powerful chip in a smartphone. And a breakthrough camera system with Depth Control. iPhone XR. It’s beautiful any way you look at it. All-new Liquid Retina display — the most advanced LCD in the industry. Even faster Face ID. The smartest, most powerful chip in a smartphone. And a breakthrough camera system with Depth Control. iPhone XR. It’s beautiful any way you look at it.   TOV — обещание иметь «красивую» штучку — вещь, которая будет нравится, в том числе по техническим характеристикам.  Just the right amount of everything. iPhone 11 | 2019  2019 2019 A new dual‑camera system captures more of what you see and love. The fastest chip ever in a smartphone and all‑day battery life let you do more and charge less. And the highest‑quality video in a smartphone, so your memories look better than ever. A new dual‑camera system captures more of what you see and love. The fastest chip ever in a smartphone and all‑day battery life let you do more and charge less. And the highest‑quality video in a smartphone, so your memories look better than ever.   TOV — три бенефита выраженные через особенности характеристик устройства.  And then there was Pro. iPhone 11 Pro | 2019  2019 2019 A transformative triple‑camera system that adds tons of capability without complexity. An unprecedented leap in battery life. And a mind‑blowing chip that doubles down on machine learning and pushes the boundaries of what a smartphone can do. Welcome to the first iPhone powerful enough to be called Pro. A transformative triple‑camera system that adds tons of capability without complexity. An unprecedented leap in battery life. And a mind‑blowing chip that doubles down on machine learning and pushes the boundaries of what a smartphone can do. Welcome to the first iPhone powerful enough to be called Pro.]]></text>
</doc>
